A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 13949-17726 FA739F
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Overview of Program - Brazil: discussion paper (Reports 015581-001), 1990 (Box 796, Reel R-9310)
  Equality -- Brazil -- Congresses; Civil society -- Brazil -- Congresses; Human rights -- Brazil -- Congresses
- Asian American women: Issues concerns and responsive human and civil rights advocacy (Reports 015581-002), undated
- Executive summary: Asian American women: Issues concerns and responsive human and civil rights advocacy (Reports 015581-003), undated
- Collection of report title pages of CEAP activities in Brazil (Reports 015582), 1997 (Box 796, Reel R-9310)
  09650685
  Center for Coordination of Marginalized Populations
  Activity report: legal program to combat racism.
  Social justice -- Brazil; Marginality, Social -- Brazil
- Ford Foundation Malaysia and Singapore semi-annual report (Reports 015583), 1969 (Box 796, Reel R-9310)
  International Division/Asia and the Pacific
  Education -- Malaysia; Agriculture -- Malaysia; Education -- Singapore; Agriculture -- Singapore; Population
- Japan and Korea: annual report: FY (Reports 015584), 1977 (Box 796, Reel R-9310)
  Philanthropy -- Japan; Philanthropy -- Korea
- Japan: annual report: FY (Reports 015585), 1976 (Box 796, Reel R-9310)
  Philanthropy -- Japan
- Philippines, martial law and the Ford Foundation Program (Reports 015586), 1973 (Box 796, Reel R-9310)
  International Division
  Charity organization -- Philippines; Endowments -- Endowments; Philanthropy -- Philippines
- Sector paper: languages: first draft (Reports 015587), 1972 (Box 796, Reel R-9310)
  Language and languages -- Southeast Asia -- Endowments; Languages in contact -- Southeast Asia
- Ford Foundation support to the social sciences in Southeast Asia (Reports 015588), 1972 (Box 796, Reel R-9311)
  Social sciences -- Southeast Asia -- Endowments; Philanthropy -- Southeast Asia; Education -- Southeast Asia -- Endowments
- Ford Foundation Program in Art and Archaeology: The Philippines, Malaysia, Thailand (Reports 015589), 1972 (Box 796, Reel R-9311)
  Arts -- Philippines; Cultural preservation -- Philippines; Arts -- Malaysia; Cultural preservation -- Malaysia; Arts -- Thailand; Cultural preservation -- Thailand; Archaeology -- Thailand; Archaeology -- Malaysia; Archaeology -- Philippines
- Office for Southeast Asia: annual report, FY (Reports 015590), 1975 (Box 796, Reel R-9311)
  International Division/South and Southeast Asia
  Philanthropy -- Southeast Asia -- Finance; Charity -- Southeast Asia -- Finance
- Office for Southeast Asia: Annual report fiscal year (Reports 015591), 1973 (Box 796, Reel R-9311)
  Annual report for the Southeast Asia office of the Ford Foundation in 1973 outlining political and economic issues in Vietnam, Thailand, Philippines, and Malaysia.
  Education; Universities and colleges; Naural resource conservation; Rural development; Population policy
- Office for Southeast Asia: Annual report fiscal year (Reports 015592), 1972 (Box 796, Reel R-9311)
  Annual report for the Southeast Asia office of the Ford Foundation in 1972, focusing the portfolio on political and economic issues in Vietnam, Philippines, and Thailand.[…]Includes interoffice memo from Howard G. Schaller to Eugene S. Staples apologizing for the quality of, and delay in sending the report.
  Universities and colleges; Education, Higher; Agriculture; Natural resources conservation
- Office for Southeast Asia: Annual report Fiscal year (Reports 015593), 1971 (Box 796, Reel R-9311)
  Annual report for the Southeast Asia office of the Ford Foundation, with special emphasis placed on the creation of the Philippines program.
  Birth control; Education; Agriculture; Public broadcasting
- Ford Foundation in the Philippines annual report, FY 1970 first draft (Reports 015594) (Box 797, Reel R-9311)
  Philanthropy -- Philippines -- Finance; Charities -- Philippines -- Fiance
- Malaysia Program in 1967, November 29 (Reports 015595) (Box 797, Reel R-9311)
  06600201
  Philanthropy -- Malaysia; Birth control -- Malaysia -- Endowments
- Annual report for FY63 and program projections (Reports 015596), 1963 (Box 797, Reel R-9311)
  Overseas Division/South and Southeast Asia
  Philanthropy -- Malaysia -- Finance; Charity -- Malaysia -- Finance
- Malaysia Field Office: status report for fiscal year 1964 and program budget for fiscal year (Reports 015597) (Box 797, Reel R-9311)
- Malaysia and Singapore: annual status report, October 1 (Reports 015598), 1966 (Box 797, Reel R-9311)
  Agriculture -- Endowments -- Finance; Education -- Endowments -- Finance; Birth control -- Endowments -- Finance; Community development -- Endowments -- Finance
- The Ford Foundation Malaysia - Singapore annual status report, 1967 plus confidential supplement (Reports 015599) (Box 797, Reel R-9311)
- The Ford Foundation Malaysia - Singapore: annual status report, 1968 (Reports 015600) (Box 797, Reel R-9311)
- EcoCentral: electronic information for Central America trade, investment, economic integration and the environment, January 25 (Reports 015601), 1997 (Box 797, Reel R-9311)
  09551435
  The University of New Mexico
  EcoCentral;Latin America Data Base (LADB)
  Sustainable development -- Latin America; Latin American studies -- Databases
- Parent education: how does it work?: Qualitative assessment of the Parents as Teachers Model of parent education (Reports 015602), 1997 (Box 797, Reel R-9311)
  09300765
  Sri International
  Community health services for children -- United States; Children -- Services for -- United States; Children -- Health and hygiene -- United States; Parents -- Services for -- United States
- Home, the first classroom: A pilot evaluation of the Northern California Parents as Teachers Project (Reports 015603), 1992 (Box 797, Reel R-9311)
  Parenting -- California, Northern -- Evaluation; Parenting -- Study and teaching -- California, Northern; Parenting -- California, Northern -- Research; Education -- Parent participation -- California, Northern -- Evaluation; Children -- Services for
- Where is the family in a child-center PAT program? An analysis of one PAT site: a qualitative assessment of the PAT model of parent education (Reports 015604), 1996 (Box 797, Reel R-9311)
  09700765
  A qualitative assessment of the PAT model of parent education
  Community health services for children -- California -- Evaluation; Children -- Services for -- California -- Evaluation; Children -- Health and hygiene -- California -- Evaluation; Parents -- Services for -- California -- Evaluation
- Parent education: why does it work? A qualitative assessment of the parents as teachers model of parent education: a proposal for the continuation of research in phase 2, February 28 (Reports 015605), 1995 (Box 797, Reel R-9311)
  Community health services for children -- United States -- Research; Children -- Services for -- United States -- Research; Children -- Health and hygiene -- United States -- Research; Parents -- Services for -- United States -- Research
- United Nations Fourth World Conference on Women: Beijing, China, 4-15 (Reports 015606), 1995 (Box 797, Reel R-9311)
  Foundation Administered Project
  Report of the Fourth World Conference on Women
  World Conference on Women (4th: 1995: Beijing, China)
  Women's rights -- Congresses; Women -- Social conditions -- Congresses
- United Nations Fourth World Conference on Women, Beijing, China, 4-15 September 1995: proposals for consideration in the preparation of a draft declaration: draft platform for action. (Reports 015607) (Box 797, Reel R-9311)
  Proposals for consideration in the preparation of a draft declaration: draft platform for action.;Draft platform for action.;Beijing declaration.;Platform for action.
  Women -- Social conditions -- Congresses; Women -- Health and hygiene -- Congresses; Women -- Employment -- Congresses; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Women's rights -- Congresses
- Provisional list of delegations to the Fourth World Conference on Women: Beijing, China, 4-15 (Reports 015608), 1995 (Box 798, Reel R-9311)
  United States and International Affairs Program - Office of the Vice President
  Programme of meetings and agenda;Journal of the United Nations
  Women's rights -- Congresses -- Attendance
- Follow up on U.S. commitments made at the UN Fourth World Conference on Women, Beijing, September 4-15, 1995 and on U.S. implementation of the Beijing declaration and platform for action (Reports 015609), 1996 (Box 798, Reel R-9311)
  Follow up on US commitments made at the UN Fourth World Conference on Women, Beijing, September 4-15, 1995 and on U.S. implementation of the Beijing declaration and platform for action;U.S. follow-up to the Fourth World Conference on Women
  Women -- United States -- Social conditions; Women -- Employment -- United States; Women's rights -- United States
- Interim directory of Chinese women's organizations, 1995. (Reports 015610) (Box 798, Reel R-9311)
  Women -- China -- Societies and clubs -- Directories
- An advocates guide to making the child support system work for children (Reports 015611), 1993 (Box 798, Reel R-9311)
  08901013
  Child support -- Law and legislation -- United States; Child welfare -- United States -- Law and legislation
- A detailed summary of key provisions of the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Block Grant of H.R. 3734: The Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of (Reports 015612), 1996 (Box 798, Reel R-9311)
  Aid to families with dependent children programs -- United States -- States; Public welfare -- United States -- States; Welfare recipients -- Employment -- United States -- States
- An evaluation of the Springfield City Schools' "Reaching Our Childre n" (ROC) Progam (Reports 015613), 1997 (Box 798, Reel R-9311)
  Ten to 15 minute interviews were conducted with each of 394 children who had completed the Springfield City Schools Reaching Our Children" (ROC) Program. Comparisons of their responses were made with corresponding responses obtained from 331 children wh
  Urban Poverty program;Rights and Social Justice; Education and Culture;United States and International Affairs Program/Office of the Vice President
  09300480
  Family Communications, Inc.
  Prejudices in children -- Prevention; Prejudices in children -- Massachusetts -- Springfield
- Different and the same: Utilization study conducted for the Ford Foundation (Reports 015614), 1997 (Box 798, Reel R-9311)
  "This report summarizes the results of a nationwide survey of the distribution and use patterns of "Different and the Same," an award-winning, prejudice-reduction curriculum produced by Family Communications, Inc." (p. i)
  Prejudice in children -- Prevention -- Curricula -- Evaluation
- How to hold a women's program forum seminar (Reports 015615), 1990 (Box 798, Reel R-9311)
- Forum '85: final report, Nairobi, Kenya (Reports 015616), 1985 (Box 798, Reel R-9311)
  09390010;L93-14
  Ford Foundation
  NGO Forum (1985: Nairobi, Kenya);World Conference to Review and Appraise the Achievements of the United Nations Decade for Women (1985: Nairobi, Kenya)
  Women -- Developing countries -- Congresses; Women -- Kenya; Non-governmental organizations -- Congresses
- The state of public radio: a report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 015617), 2001 (Box 798, Reel R-9311)
  "This study was commissioned by John Phillip Santos in February 2001, with the intention of providing the Ford Foundation [with] a clear understanding of current conditions in the public radio sector. Given awareness that much is changing in this sector..
  Public radio -- United States -- Evaluation
- Radiografia de un proceso de paz: Borron y cuenta nueva? X-ray of a peace process: Starting over (Reports 015618), 1995 (Box 798, Reel R-9311)
  Report on the socio-political condition of El Salvador.[…]Report is written entirely in Spanish. Translation of title is hand-written on title page of report.
  09251294
  Universidad Centroamericana "Jose Simeon Canas"
  X-ray of a peace process: Starting over?
  Human rights advocacy -- El Salvador; Peace -- El Salvador
- Tiempos de crisis, tiempos de mujeres Times of crisis, times of women (Reports 015619), 1996 (Box 798, Reel R-9311, Box 799)
  09000568
  National Autonomous University of Mexico (UNAM)
  Times of crisis, times of women
  Women agricultural laborers -- Mexico; Rural women -- Mexico -- Social conditions
- Corporate involvement initiative (POM), January 30 (Reports 015620), 2001 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Endowments -- Finance; Corporate finance -- Endowments
- Community youth development and youth leadership for development (POM), January 22 (Reports 015621), 2001 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Community development -- Finance; Youth -- Services for -- Finance
- Arts and cultural archives: preservation and access and creating an environment for contemporary art and tolerance and cultural diversity through the media (POM), February 26 (Reports 015622), 2001 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Initiatives: Arts and Cultural Archives: Preservation and Access -- Creating an Environment for Contemporary Art -- Tolerance and Cultural Diversity through the Media.
  Arts -- Preservation -- Russia (Federation); Culture -- Study and teaching; Mass media -- Ethics -- Russia (Federation)
- Sectoral workforce development initiative and changing structure of work initiative and workforce development policy initiative (POM), October 12 (Reports 015623), 2000 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Labor supply -- United States; Labor policy -- United States; Community development
- Savings and wealth building (POM), October 25 (Reports 015624), 2000 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Initiative seeks to alleviate poverty and to assist low-income populations build personal savings through individual development accounts (IDA)
  Economic development; Poor -- United States
- The folklore initiative (POM) (Reports 015625), 2001 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  The Folklore initiative has two broad aspects: Folklore studies and scholarship that aims to generate a deeper understanding of peoples' cultures;and Folklore activism and practice that foster creative expression and outreach in the public domain.
  Folklore -- India; Multiculturalism -- India
- Institutionalizing participatory forest management and forest resources-based enterprise development (POM) (Reports 015626), 2001 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  State-owned forests and marginally productive wetlands are vital to the substance and income of the extremely poor who constitute 35 percent of India's almost one billion people. Access to these common property resources is defined by the complexities of...
  Social forestry programs -- India; Land use, Rural -- India; Wetlands conservation -- India; Natural resources -- Conservation -- India
- Internationalizing new work in the performing arts and strengthening arts and cultural institutions and expanding the role of the arts in civil dialogue (POM), August 23 (Reports 015627), 2000 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Three initiatives in the Education, Media, Arts and Culture Unit.
  Cultural awareness -- Endowments -- United States; Performing arts -- Endowments -- United States; Civic improvement -- United States; Mass media and culture
- Reconstructing the law to advance women's rights and revisioning and actualizing the economic and social rights of women (POM), July 12 (Reports 015628), 2001 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Women's rights; Human rights -- United States; Women's rights -- Minorities; Sex discrimination; Women -- Economic conditions
- Mobilizing communities for improved reproductive health and research and advocacy towards sexual and reproductive freedom (POM), March 2 (Reports 015629), 2001 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Latin America and the Caribbean
  Reproductive health -- Chile; Reproductive health -- Argentina; Reproductive health -- Columbia; Reproductive health -- Peru; Reproductive rights
- Developing a culture of citizenship in the Arab world and building constituencies for peace in the Middle East (POM), February 6 (Reports 015630), 2001 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Civil society -- International cooperation; Citizenship -- Egypt; Citizenship -- Palestine
- Strengthening development finance institutions (DFES) and fostering an enabling policy environment for microfinance (DFES) (POM), October 24 (Reports 015631), 2000 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Microfinance -- Nigeria; Economic development -- Nigeria; Environmental policy -- Africa, West
- Amazon basin initiative for sustainable development and conservation-based community development for the Atlantic forest region and crosscutting portfolio component: an assets- and rights-based agenda in support of indigenous peoples and the environme (Reports 015632), 1999 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Community development -- Brazil; Indigenous peoples -- Brazil; Environmental protection -- Brazil; Sustainable development -- Brazil
- Broadening participation in governance and Equity and Participation in Civil Society (EPICS) (POM) (Reports 015633), 1999 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Democratization -- Africa, East; Politics and government -- Citizen participation -- Africa, East; Political participation -- Africa, East
- New educators for changing communities (POM) (Reports 015634), 1998 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Education, Knowledge and Religion Unit of the Education, Media, Arts and Culture program education reform initiative.
  Educators, American; Education -- Aims and objectives -- United States; Educational change -- United States
- Enforcement of human rights and local support for human rights (POM) (Reports 015635), 1999 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Human rights -- Africa, West; Human rights advocacy -- Africa, West; Democratization -- Africa, West
- Informed advocacy for reproductive health and women's health and economic empowerment (POM) (Reports 015636), 1999 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Reproductive health -- Africa, West; Youth -- Health and hygiene -- Africa, West; Women -- Health and hygiene -- Africa, West; Poverty -- Africa, West
- Understanding decentralization and citizen participation in local governance and improving public service (POM), September 7 (Reports 015637), 1999 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Decentralization in government -- Indonesia; Politics and government -- Citizen participation -- Indonesia; Political participation -- Indonesia
- Building a mosaic of sustainable land uses and ownership that benefit low-income communities in the Amazon (POM), October 4 (Reports 015638), 2005 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  "Long-term goals: 1) To ensure greater access to land and expand development opportunities for low-income traditional peoples' communities in the Amazon Deforestation Belt [and] 2) To promote a socio-environmental agenda for villages, towns and cities in[…]Program Officer Memo of the Brazil office, Asset Building and Community Development program division for the Environment and Development field.
  Land use, Rural -- Brazil; Land tenure -- Brazil; Community development -- Brazil; Economics -- Sociological aspects; Deforestation -- Amazon River Region; Deforestation -- Brazil; Deforestation -- Economic aspects -- Amazon River Region; Deforestation
- Strengthening international cultural enterprises for sustainable livelihoods and rethinking public humanities in the U.S. (POM), April 3 (Reports 015639), 2001 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  "Principal locations of Work: Africa, Caribbean, Latin America and U.S." (p.1)
  Cultural awareness -- International cooperation; Cultural policy -- International cooperation; Cultural awareness -- Endowments; Culture and globalization -- International cooperation; Community development -- International cooperation
- Promoting anit-racist law, public policy and culture and improving gender relations and women's rights (POM), February 28 (Reports 015640), 2000 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Human rights advocacy -- Endowments; Human rights -- Politics and government -- International cooperation; Race discrimination -- Law and legislation
- Interdisciplinary knowledge-building for a new civic education and leadership for a re-visioned academy in the 21st century (POM), May 19 (Reports 015641), 2000 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Education, Higher; Education -- Curricula; Educators -- Training of; Curriculum planning; Curriculum change
- Community forestry and community based natural resources management in eastern Indonesia (POM) (Reports 015642), 2000 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Forestry and community -- Indonesia; Natural resources -- Economic aspects; Poverty -- Indonesia
- Reproductive health and family equity and youth development and adolescent health (POM), December 20 (Reports 015643), 1999 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Reproductive health -- Africa, East; HIV infections -- Africa -- Prevention; HIV infections -- Study and teaching -- Africa, East; AIDS (Disease) -- Social aspects -- Africa, East; Reproductive rights
- Human Rights in Israel and equality for the Palestinian minority in Israel and peaceful resolution of Israeli-Palestinian conflict (POM), January 14 (Reports 015644), 2000 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Human rights -- Israel; Palestinian Arabs -- Civil rights
- Increasing the effectiveness of human rights advocacy activities and enhancing the role of legal institutions in human rights protection and promoting the cultural legitimacy of human rights in the Arab/Islamic context (POM), August 30 (Reports 015645), 1999 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Human rights -- Middle East; Human rights -- Africa, North; Human rights -- International coOperation
- Strengthening education governance and combating African-Brazilian education disadvantage (POM), March 3 (Reports 015646), 2000 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Initiatives: Strengthening Education Governance -- Combating African-Brazilian Education Disadvantage.
  Ford Foundation. Field office Rio de Janeiro
  Education reform -- Brazil
- Religion and culture: meeting the challenge of pluralism (POM) (Reports 015647), 1998 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Religious pluralism; Leadership in women; Civil society -- Religious aspects; Religions -- Relations
- Developing equity initiative and regional infrastructure for firm growth and job quality (POM), October 3 (Reports 015648), 2000 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Unemployment -- United States; Underemployment -- United States; Small businesses -- United States; Community development -- United States
- Civil society and globalization and knowledge building and civil society and revitalizing the US nonprofit sector (POM), June 15 (Reports 015649), 1999 (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Civil society -- United States; Equality -- United States; Nonprofit organization -- United States
- Northwest Forest Plan 1995: accomplishment report (Reports 015650) (Box 799, Reel R-9311)
  Forest policy -- Northwest, Pacific; Ecosystem management -- Northwest, Pacific; Forest biological diversity conservation -- Research -- Northwest, Pacific
- Capacity-building for cultural and arts organizations and community access and involvement and cultural policy (POM), October 25 (Reports 015651), 1999 (Box 800, Reel R-9311)
  Multiculturalism -- Indonesia; Community development -- Cultural assimilation -- Indonesia; Arts, Indonesian
- Promoting effective, accountable and participatory governance and civil society and structural change: strengthening capacity through new partnerships (POM), November 22 (Reports 015652), 1999 (Box 800, Reel R-9311)
  Public policy -- Citizen participation -- Brazil; Social justice -- Brazil
- Fostering critical dialogue on development and promoting innovative approaches to community asset building and supporting efforts to integrate youth in community development processes (POM), December 20 (Reports 015653), 1999 (Box 800, Reel R-9311)
  Community development -- Egypt; Community development -- Palestine; Community development -- Middle East; Community development -- North Africa; Youth; Community leadership